Guide to the Harold J. Mayers Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harold J. Mayers papers
1948-1976
MS 938
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(4 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, administrative files, subject files, printed materials and reports of Harold J. Mayers. The papers also contain files from six national and Washington, D.C., public health and tuberculosis organizations, including the American Public Health Association and National Tuberculosis Association. These papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Mayers, Harold J.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Harold J. Mayers, 1979.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. UNITED MINE WORKERS OF AMERICA, WELFARE AND RETIREMENT FUND PAPERS. II. ORGANIZATIONS.
Scope and Contents
HAROLD J. MAYERS PAPERS, 1948-1976
4 paige boxes; received from Harold J. Mayers
The papers consist of correspondence, administrative files, subject files, printed materials and reports of Harold J. Mayers. The papers also contain files from six national and Washington, D.C., public health and tuberculosis organizations, including the American Public Health Association and National Tuberculosis Association. These papers form part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection.
Biographical / Historical
Harold J. Mayers was a hospital consultant with the United Mine Workers of America Welfare and Retirement Fund from 1946 to 1976. The bulk of the papers consists of the correspondence files and administrative records from Mayers' tenure at the Fund. The early papers are fragmentary; the papers from 1973 to 1975 are more complete. In addition, the collection contains Mayers' files from five national and local (Washington, D.C.) public health and tuberculosis organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Hospital care; Working class -- Hospital care; Working class -- Medical care; Medicine; Public health; Hospital consultants; Labor movement -- Hospital care; Labor -- Hospital care; Labor movement -- Medical care; Labor -- Medical care; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Mayers, Harold J.; American Public Health Association; National Tuberculosis Association; United Mine Workers of America. Welfare and Retirement Fund
- UNITED MINE WORKERS OF AMERICA, WELFARE AND RETIREMENT FUND PAPERS, 1948-1976; Series I
  - Correspondence
    - 1948-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 January - May (Box 1)
    - 1974 May - October (Box 1)
    - 1974 November - December (Box 1)
    - 1975 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, reprints, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence re: retirement, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Files
    - Daily log, 1974 Jul, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Field trip reports, 1948-1952 (Box 1)
    - Internal administration: memoranda, reports, 1948-1973, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Personnel announcements, 1948-1975 (Box 1)
  - Subject Files
    - Appalachian Regional Hospitals, Inc.
      - Correspondence, reports, 1974 (Box 1)
      - Negotiations, memoranda, planning manual, 1974 (Box 1)
      - Contract, drafts, correspondence, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Caulfield, Stephen: correspondence, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Clinic Health Care Plan, Inception: memoranda, reports, 1970 (Box 1)
    - Clinic Health Care Plan, Medical Management: memoranda, reports, 1962, 1970, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Conference on Technology and Health Care Systems: memoranda, clippings, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Draper, Warren F.: correspondence, speeches, 1951, 1958, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Faber, Joan K., "A Thousand Bedsides," drafts, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - Garfield Plan, 1951 May (Box 2)
    - Hospitals: contracts, 1948 (Box 2)
    - Kerr, Lorin E.: articles, correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 2)
    - London Conference: program, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Memphis Health Center, Inc.: notes, correspondence, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Migratory Labor Health Association Hospital: correspondence, policy statements, operations manual, 1945-1947 (Box 2)
    - Physician Extenders, Massachusetts Institute of Technology: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Quality Assurance in Hospital Care Meeting: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Respiratory diseases: correspondence, memoranda, reports, 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - Salhaven: correspondence, 1956-1965 (Box 2)
    - Transit Employees' Health and Welfare Fund: memoranda, print material, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Writings (Mayer), 1952-1953, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Reports, Print Material
    - Annual reports, Welfare and Retirement Fund, 1951-1971 (Box 2)
    - Pension plan, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Memos re: hospital service to Fund beneficiaries as a percent of total hospital service, 1969, 1971 (Box 2)
    - "An analysis of the mental health services of the United Mine Workers of America Welfare and Retirement Fund"; related correspondence and print material, Circa 1972 (Box 3)
    - Mental Health, addendum, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Historical file, 1947-1957
      - Reprints re: Welfare and Retirement Fund (Box 3)
      - 10 Memorial hospitals, dedicatory pamphlet, articles, Circa 1956 (Box 3)
      - John L. Lewis: transcripts of congressional testimony, 1953, 1957 (Box 3)
    - Operating Procedures, 1947 (Box 3)
    - Operating Procedures, Parts I-VI, Circa 1950 (Box 3)
    - Operating Manual, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Weinerman, E. Richard, "Report of a Survey of the Miners Memorial Association 1960-1961"
- ORGANIZATIONS, 1948-1976; Series II
  - American Public Health Association
    - Subcommittee on Social Action: annual report, 1974 (Box 3)
    - Washington Research Project: correspondence, minutes, 1967-1968, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Committee for the Nation's Health: newsletters, 1950-1954 (Box 3)
  - District of Columbia Public Health Association
    - Constitution, 1963 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous papers and correspondence, 1963, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Reports, minutes, correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 3)
    - Reports, minutes, correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 4)
    - News, 1963-1971
  - District of Columbia Tuberculosis Association
    - Minutes, correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 4)
  - National Tuberculosis and Respiratory Disease Association, Committee on Metropolitan Problems
    - Minutes, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Memoranda, print material, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
    - Reports, correspondence, 1969 (Box 4)
  - National Tuberculosis Association, Christmas Seal Campaign Committee: correspondence, memoranda, 1967 (Box 4)
  - National Tuberculosis Association, Committee on Treatment of Tuberculosis Patients in Hospitals: reports, correspondence, 1967 (Box 4)